Brecht, Arnold; Papers ger024
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
- Writings by Others, 1939-1974; 5; 31 file folders
  - Papers from the New School for Social Research Fortieth Anniversary Bonn Conference, 1974 June 20-1974 June 21; 5.24 (Box 15 (5-Writings by Others), Folder 24-31)
    - Morgenthau, Hans J. "Science of Peace: A Rationalist Utopia", Undated (Box 15 (5-Writings by Others), Folder 27)
    - Picht, George. "Zum Begriff des Friedens", Undated (Box 15 (5-Writings by Others), Folder 28)
    - Speier, Hans. "The Chances for Peace", Undated (Box 15 (5-Writings by Others), Folder 29)
    - Vidich, Arthur J. "Social Conflict in the Era of Détente: New Roles for Ideologues, Revolutionaries and Youth", Undated (Box 15 (5-Writings by Others), Folder 30)
    - Weizsäcker, C. F. von. "Konnen wir für den Frieden planen?", Undated (Box 15 (5-Writings by Others), Folder 31)
- Collections of Materials on Various Topics of Interest, 6; 79 file folders
  This series contains primarily clippings assembled by Brecht on various topics, including a number of folders of clippings pertaining to the Reich budget during Brecht's years as the representative of Prussia in German Reichsrat and rapporteur for the federal budget (1927-1933).
  Arranged chronologically and alphabetically.
  - Outbreak of World War I, 1914 (Box 15 (6-Collections of Materials on Various Topics of Inte), Folder 32)
  - Russian secret documents, 1918 (Box 15 (6-Collections of Materials on Various Topics of Inte), Folder 33)
  - Peace settlements, 1919 (Box 15 (6-Collections of Materials on Various Topics of Inte), Folder 34)
    Weissbuch. Vorgeschichte des Waffenstillstands -- press clippings.
  - Statements of the Deutsche Nationalversammlung, 1919 (Box 15 (6-Collections of Materials on Various Topics of Inte), Folder 35)
  - World War I, Undated (Box 15 (6-Collections of Materials on Various Topics of Inte), Folder 36)
  - Weimar Constitution celebrations, 1921-1928 (Box 15 (6-Collections of Materials on Various Topics of Inte), Folder 37)
  - Weimar Republic, Undated (Box 15 (6-Collections of Materials on Various Topics of Inte), Folder 38)
  - Battleship (Panzerschiff), 1927 (Box 15 (6-Collections of Materials on Various Topics of Inte), Folder 39)
  - Reich budget, 1927 (Box 15 (6-Collections of Materials on Various Topics of Inte), Folder 40)
  - Reich budget; Young plan, 1928 (Box 15 (6-Collections of Materials on Various Topics of Inte), Folder 41)
  - Reich budget, 1929 (Box 15 (6-Collections of Materials on Various Topics of Inte), Folder 42)
  - Reich budget, 1930 (Box 15 (6-Collections of Materials on Various Topics of Inte), Folder 43)
  - Reich budget, 1931 (Box 15 (6-Collections of Materials on Various Topics of Inte), Folder 44)
  - Reich budget, 1932 (Box 15 (6-Collections of Materials on Various Topics of Inte), Folder 45)
    Including Brecht speech, June 28, 1932.
  - The Enabling Act (Ermächtigungsgesetz), 1933 March 24 (Box 15 (6-Collections of Materials on Various Topics of Inte), Folder 46)
  - Yalta and Dumbarton Oaks, 1945 (Box 15 (6-Collections of Materials on Various Topics of Inte), Folder 47)
  - Bonner Grundgesetz, 1948-1949 (Box 15 (6-Collections of Materials on Various Topics of Inte), Folder 48)
  - Death of Joseph Stalin, 1953 (Box 15 (6-Collections of Materials on Various Topics of Inte), Folder 49)
  - Columbia University Bicentennial Celebration, 1954 October (Box 15 (6-Collections of Materials on Various Topics of Inte), Folder 50)
  - Re-unification of East and West Germany, 1955; 1958 (Box 15 (6-Collections of Materials on Various Topics of Inte), Folder 51)
  - European Summit Conference, Paris, 1972 (Box 15 (6-Collections of Materials on Various Topics of Inte), Folder 52)
  - Clippings on various topics, 1953-1955 (Box 15 (6-Collections of Materials on Various Topics of Inte), Folder 53)
  - Miscellaneous clippings and notes, Undated (Box 15 (6-Collections of Materials on Various Topics of Inte), Folder 54)
  - American Securities and Bonds, Undated (Box 16 (6-Collections of Materials on Various Topics of Inte), Folder 1)
  - Anti-trust laws, monopolies, Undated (Box 16 (6-Collections of Materials on Various Topics of Inte), Folder 2)
  - Bibliography (works by others), 1976 (Box 16 (6-Collections of Materials on Various Topics of Inte), Folder 3)
  - Churchill and British history, 1930s-1950s (Box 16 (6-Collections of Materials on Various Topics of Inte), Folder 4)
  - Concentration camps, Undated (Box 16 (6-Collections of Materials on Various Topics of Inte), Folder 5)
  - Democracy, Undated (Box 16 (6-Collections of Materials on Various Topics of Inte), Folder 6)
  - Housing, municipal police and courts, Undated; clippings, notes (Box 16 (6-Collections of Materials on Various Topics of Inte), Folder 7)
  - Intolerance, Undated (Box 16 (6-Collections of Materials on Various Topics of Inte), Folder 8)
  - Makaria Altherrenverband, Undated (Box 16 (6-Collections of Materials on Various Topics of Inte), Folder 9)
  - New School for Social Research. Miscellaneous materials, Undated (Box 16 (6-Collections of Materials on Various Topics of Inte), Folder 10)
  - Old constitutions, Undated (Box 16 (6-Collections of Materials on Various Topics of Inte), Folder 11)
  - Pabst, Waldemar, Undated (Box 16 (6-Collections of Materials on Various Topics of Inte), Folder 12)
  - Public Administration, Civil Service, Undated; clippings, notes (Box 16 (6-Collections of Materials on Various Topics of Inte), Folder 13)
  - Rathenau, Walther, Undated (Box 16 (6-Collections of Materials on Various Topics of Inte), Folder 14)
  - Rathenau, Walther. Sketchbooks, Undated (Box 16 (6-Collections of Materials on Various Topics of Inte), Folder 15)
  - Reichssiegel -- Official Seal of the Third Reich, Undated (Box 16 (6-Collections of Materials on Various Topics of Inte), Folder 16)
  - Smaller Countries: Austria -- Latin and Central America, Undated (Box 16 (6-Collections of Materials on Various Topics of Inte), Folder 17)
  - Smaller Countries: The Netherlands -- Yugoslavia, Undated (Box 16 (6-Collections of Materials on Various Topics of Inte), Folder 18)
  - State, Civil Service, Welfare Relief, Undated (Box 16 (6-Collections of Materials on Various Topics of Inte), Folder 19)
  - U.S. Constitution, Declaration of Independence, Flag, etc, Undated (Box 16 (6-Collections of Materials on Various Topics of Inte), Folder 20)
  - U.S. Government tax revenues & expenditures, 1955 (Box 16 (6-Collections of Materials on Various Topics of Inte), Folder 21)
  - U.S. Presidency, Cabinet Members, Undated (Box 16 (6-Collections of Materials on Various Topics of Inte), Folder 22)
  - War, Undated; clippings, notes (Box 16 (6-Collections of Materials on Various Topics of Inte), Folder 23)
  - Weimar Republic, flag, national anthem, Undated (Box 16 (6-Collections of Materials on Various Topics of Inte), Folder 24)
  - Weimar Republic, Undated (Box 16 (6-Collections of Materials on Various Topics of Inte), Folder 25)